Vu Manh Cuong

Date of birth March 1st, 1991

Gender Male

Phone 0932132971

Email cuongvu0103@gmail.com

Address 88/4 Le Loi Street, Hoc Mon District, HCMC, Viet Nam

Website http://vumanhcuongit.github.io

SUMMARY

In the whole role of my engineering practice include providing solutions, architecture, and projects in various verticals. I currently work as a software engineer specialising in Elixir and distributed systems. Love learning new things or tools everyday. If I do not know something I will learn it.

EDUCATION

2009 - 2013 VNUHCM - University of Science

Bachelor of Engineering

Computer Software Engineering

WORK EXPERIENCE

March 2018 - Present

Yojee

Backend Engineer

Architect and implement enterprise applications using test-driven development in Elixir, Phoenix and PostgreSQL:

- Develop Webhook system which helps clients to receive latest status of deliveries so that they can use the information to update their system and do not waste resources by using API.
- Build notification system which notifies events triggered by drivers / partners that require dispatcher's attention and/or action.
- Build broadcast feature, with the feature dispatcher can send assignment to several of drivers at once.
- Develop delivery management system which allows drivers to get new assignments, suggestions, as well as have access to collect signatures and photos as Proof of Delivery to have a smooth delivery experience.
- · Maintain API for mobile and front-end application.

July 2016 - October 2017

Quoine

Backend Engineer

Develop an Elixir application which has standardised and automated mechanisms to provide financial data to consumer

applications:

- Get and clean data from many other sources: foreign exchange rates, trading and internal data.
- Standardise data into packet and send them to Kafka.
- Gather metrics, visualises data, and alerts operators when things appear to be broken.

Develop financial services to perform hedging strategy in trading which takes profit from the price difference between Quoine and competitors:

- Design and implement data tables: external order and execution. These tables store data and handle business logic.
- Check external exchanges API documents to build client wrappers by creating Ruby gems. These API wrappers are essential to place external orders and check hedge executions.
- Create a dashboard that helps admin monitors orders and profit. Querying data in a cache is significant because this dashboard also gives the admin the ability to retrieve historical data.

Contribute to event processing system and workflows for calculating user's balance. These services are built to feature:

- · Subscribe to events.
- Calculate user's balance from event data.
- · Check and correct balance periodically.

Analyse and solve performance issues: memory leak, memory bloat, slow requests and queries:

- Check New Relic's each week to identify and fix bottlenecks.
- Monitor the performance and point out performance regression.
- Rewrite slow queries, add indexes and remove duplicate ones.

July 2015 - June 2016

MortgageClub

Ruby on Rails Developer

Build a platform that helps home buyers can easily apply, shop, and lock in the best loan in minutes.

Extremely use test driven development (RSpec and Cucumber).

September 2014 - April 2015

Tech in Asia

Ruby on Rails Developer

Work on Techlist.asia - Asia's first platform for investors and founders. Techlist was an online service to help investors track startups in Asia.

Develop an automated system to compute and publish reports as charts.

Build and maintain startup and investor's pages in which user can search and track them.

SKILLS

Programming language	Elixir, Ruby and Python.
Database	PostgreSQL and Redis.
Testing	ExUnit, RSpec and Cucumber.

CERTIFICATIONS AND AWARDS

September 2018	Practical Predictive Analytics: Models and Methods(Coursera)
September 2018	Supervised Learning with scikit-learn(DataCamp)
August 2018	Data Manipulation at Scale: Systems and Algorithms(Coursera)
September 2015	First prize in East Agile Hack Day